export const questions3 = [
  {
    question: 'Which rocket was the first in history to reach outer space?',
    options: ['V-2', 'RN R-7', 'Saturn V', 'Falcon 1'],
    correctAnswer: 'V-2',
  },
  {
    question: 'When was the first launch of the V-2 rocket?',
    options: ['1957', '1961', '1944', '1975'],
    correctAnswer: '1944',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What rocket was used for the first launch of the Sputnik-1 satellite?',
    options: ['RN R-7', 'Redstone', 'Atlas', 'Titan'],
    correctAnswer: 'RN R-7',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was the first astronaut to fly into space?',
    options: ['Neil Armstrong', 'Yuri Gagarin', 'Allen Shepard', 'John Glenn'],
    correctAnswer: 'Yuri Gagarin',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which rocket was the main vehicle for the Apollo program?',
    options: ['Space Shuttle', 'Saturn V', 'Soyuz', 'Atlas'],
    correctAnswer: 'Saturn V',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which country was the first to launch a satellite into orbit?',
    options: ['USSR', 'the United States', 'China', 'France'],
    correctAnswer: 'USSR',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which satellite became the first artificial satellite of the Earth?',
    options: ['Explorer 1', 'Sputnik 1', 'Telstar 1', 'Vanguard 1'],
    correctAnswer: 'Sputnik 1',
  },
  {
    question: 'What rocket was used for the first manned flight to orbit?',
    options: [
      'Mercury-Redstone',
      'Vostok 1',
      'Gemini Titan',
      'Apollo Saturn V',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Vostok 1',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which rocket was the first to send people to the moon?',
    options: ['Soyuz', 'Falcon Heavy', 'Ariane 5', 'Saturn V'],
    correctAnswer: 'Saturn V',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which launch was the beginning of the space race between the USA and the USSR?',
    options: [
      'The launch of Apollo 11',
      'Launch of Vostok 1',
      'Launch of Sputnik-1',
      'Space Shuttle launch',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Launch of Sputnik-1',
  },
];
